[{"question": "Choose correct answer..\n#include<stdio.h>\nmain()\n{\n\t/* Multi Line Comment\n\tThis line is ignored by compiler\n\t*/\n\tprintf(\"Hello C..\"); \n}", "option1": "A) #include is a Preprocessor Directive", "option2": "B) <stdio.h> is a header file with predefined functions like printf, scanf etc", "option3": "C) #include\nmain()\n{\n\n}\nis a mandatory function to be included in every C Program.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Correct way of commenting a single line is.?", "option1": "A) /*printf(\"Hello C..\");\nprintf(\"How are you.\");\n\u00a0", "option2": "B) //printf(\"Hello C..\");\nprintf(\"How are you.\");", "option3": "C) /*printf(\"Hello C..\");\nprintf(\"How are you.\");*/", "option4": "D) /printf(\"Hello C..\");/\nprintf(\"How are you.\");", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "Single Line Comment // is also called.?", "option1": "A) C++ Style Comment", "option2": "B) Java Style Comment", "option3": "C) PHP Style Comment", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "Choose the correct answer.?", "option1": "A) Digraph <: represents [\nDigraph :> represents ]\nDigraph <% reprsents {\nDigraph %> reprsents }\nDigraph %: represents #\nDigraph %:%: represents ##", "option2": "B) Digraph <: represents ]\nDigraph :> represents [\nDigraph <% reprsents {\nDigraph %> reprsents }\nDigraph %: represents #\nDigraph %:%: represents ##", "option3": "C) Digraph <: represents ]\nDigraph :> represents [\nDigraph <% reprsents }\nDigraph %> reprsents {\nDigraph %: represents $\nDigraph %:%: represents $$", "option4": "D) Digraph <: represents {\nDigraph :> represents }\nDigraph <% reprsents [\nDigraph %> reprsents ]\nDigraph %: represents /\nDigraph %:%: represents //", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "What is an Identifier in C Language.?", "option1": "A) Name of a Function or Variable", "option2": "B) Name of a Macros", "option3": "C) Name of Structure or Union", "option4": "D) All the above.", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "An Identifier may contain.?", "option1": "A) Letters a-z, A-Z in Basic character set.\nUnicode alphabet characters other languages", "option2": "B) Underscore _ symbol", "option3": "C) Numbers 0 to 9\nUnicode Numbers in other languages", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}, {"question": "What is the number of characters used to distinguish Identifier or Names of Functions and Global variables.?", "option1": "A) 31", "option2": "B) 32", "option3": "C) 33", "option4": "D) 28", "ans": "A"}, {"question": "What is length of an Identifier that is unique for Non Global Variables and Non Function Names.?", "option1": "A) 32", "option2": "B) 63", "option3": "C) 64", "option4": "D) 68", "ans": "B"}, {"question": "An Identifier can start with.?", "option1": "A) Alphabet", "option2": "B) Underscore ( _ ) sign", "option3": "C) Any character that can be typed on a keyboard", "option4": "D) Option A & Option B", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " C Programs are used in .?", "option1": "A) Any Electronic device which works on some logic and Operating System.", "option2": "B) Washing machine", "option3": "C) Fridge, Microwave Ovens", "option4": "D) All the above.", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " What are the types of Constants in C Language.?", "option1": "A) Primary Constants", "option2": "B) Secondary Constants", "option3": "C) Basic Constants and Advanced Constants", "option4": "D) Primary Constants and Secondary Constants", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Choose correct statements", "option1": "A) A constant value does not change.\nA variable value can change according to needs.", "option2": "B) A constant can change its values.\nA variable can have one constant value only.", "option3": "C) There is no restriction on number of values for constants or variables.", "option4": "D) Constants and Variables can not be used in a singe main function.", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " Find an integer constant.", "option1": "A) 3.145", "option2": "B) 34", "option3": "C) \"125\"", "option4": "D) None of the above", "ans": "B"}, {"question": " Find a Floating Point constant.", "option1": "A) 12.3E5", "option2": "B) 12e34", "option3": "C) 125.34857", "option4": "D) All the above.", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " Find a Character constant.", "option1": "A) 'A'\n'a'\n", "option2": "B) '1'\n'9'\n", "option3": "C) '$'\n'#'\n", "option4": "D) All the above.", "ans": "D"}, {"question": " A Variable of a particular type can hold only a constant of the same type. Choose right answer.", "option1": "A) TRUE", "option2": "B) FALSE", "option3": "C) It depends on the place the variable is declared.", "option4": "D) None of the above.", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " Choose a right statement.", "option1": "A) int myage = 10;\nint my_age = 10;", "option2": "B) int myage = 10;\nint my,age = 10;", "option3": "C) int myage = 10;\nint my age = 10;", "option4": "D) All are right", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " Number of Keywords present in C Language are .?", "option1": "A) 32", "option2": "B) 34", "option3": "C) 62", "option4": "D) 64", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " Each statement in a C program should end with.?", "option1": "A) Semicolon ;", "option2": "B) Colon :", "option3": "C) Period . (dot symbol)", "option4": "D) None of the above.", "ans": "A"}, {"question": " Choose a correct statement.", "option1": "A) C Compiler converts your C program into machine readable language.", "option2": "B) C Editor allows you to type C Programs. It is just like a Notepad with extra options.", "option3": "C) Console shows the output of a C Program if it is text output.", "option4": "D) All the above", "ans": "D"}]
